The Transformer, a novel neural network architecture
based solely on attention mechanisms, outperforms existing
models in machine translation and other tasks.
The researchers identified this challenge: Recurrent neural
networks used in sequence transduction models present
inherent limitations in parallelization and computational efficiency
due to their sequential nature.
Their approach was as follows: The Transformer
architecture dispenses with recurrence and convolutional operations,
introducing an encoder-decoder structure based entirely on
self-attention and multi-head attention mechanisms.
The research yielded these results: The Transformer
achieves state-of-the-art results in machine translation tasks,
outperforming previous models by over 2 BLEU
on the WMT 2014 English-to-German translation task.
Looking ahead, The authors propose exploring customized attention
functions, combining the Transformer with other architectures, and
extending it to a wider range of tasks.